hey everybody welcome to this b1 english
listening practice video
you can use this video to practice your
listening and comprehension
as i speak before we start remember to
sign up for our one dollar
listening practice seminars at
polyglossa.com
and download my free listening time
podcast
so you can practice your listening
skills
[Music]
so today i'm going to talk about
creativity
i feel like this is a topic that doesn't
get discussed much outside of certain
artistic communities
however i think it's something important
that plays a role in all of our lives
first of all let's try to define
creativity one of the definitions i
found was the following
the use of the imagination or original
ideas
this is exactly how i'd describe it when
you produce something original
whether it be an idea solution game or
work of art
you're being creative so that would mean
that the opposite of being creative
is doing things or copying things that
other people do
or tell you to do in many situations
this isn't a bad thing
there are a plethora of situations that
don't call for creativity
in these cases the best thing to do is
to follow orders plans or processes that
are already laid out for you
when you're on the job it's probably not
good for you to always try to be
creative
you might actually end up making things
worse that way
however there are many situations in
which creativity is good
and so we should try to foster that in
ourselves and in our children
i mentioned children because in my
opinion creativity is an essential part
of being a child
for example when i was a young kid i
played outside practically every day
with my neighbors
and the games we played involved a lot
of creativity on our part
we had to imagine certain scenarios
think of rules to follow and invent many
aspects of these games as we went along
this called for creative thinking
because we had to make these games
interesting and fun
however nowadays this type of play isn't
quite as popular as it used to be
sure many kids invent games and play
outside but it's becoming increasingly
normal for kids to spend hours in front
of a screen every day
their source of entertainment comes from
what they're shown on this device
and so they don't have to be creative to
have fun some people might not consider
this that big of a problem
but i do i've worked with many kids in
different contexts and i've definitely
seen the importance of creativity in
kids lives
i've taught many kids that don't have
this tendency to be creative
and in my opinion this has had some
negative effects on their lives
in many cases these kids have worse
communication skills
and they seem to have less
self-confidence however on the other
hand i've known some kids who probably
had too much freedom in their creativity
and this also seemed to have some
negative effects for example these kids
sometimes had trouble following rules
in summary i think that we should create
an environment for our kids that fosters
creativity
but i also think that we should rein in
that creativity at times
so how can we train our creativity and
become more creative in general
i think the best way to do this is to do
creative activities
there are plenty of artistic activities
that we can try our hand at
for example you might want to try
drawing or painting
i'm certainly not good at either of
these but i do engage in them from time
to time and i think it really benefits
me
it takes me out of my comfort zone and
forces me to think and move in a way
that's not too familiar to me
another creative activity that you might
want to try is creative writing
not many people engage in this activity
on a regular basis but they should
it makes you think of words and phrases
that you might not normally use
and it forces you to describe things in
a way that you're not used to
needless to say fiction writers are some
of the most creative people out there
i'm sure there are also many other
activities that you could think of that
could help you train your creativity
okay now i'm going to ask you three
questions about today's video
write your answers in a comment down
below number one
what's the opposite of being creative
number two
what's one reason why many kids don't
play creative games nowadays
and number three what's one activity
that you can do to train your creativity
all right before we go remember to sign
up for our one dollar listening practice
seminars
and download our listening time podcast
to practice your listening skills
and of course subscribe to the channel
click on the bell
and follow us on instagram i'll see you
next time
you